(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
FBKINGDOM PROLOGUE
フブキキングダム プロローグ
Fubuki Kingdom Prologue
カガリビト
作詞・作曲：millstones
Kagaribito
Lyrics/Composition: millstones
静まり返り
Silent and still,
眠る街を駆けゆく
running through the sleeping city.
吹き抜け踊る
Blowing through and dancing,
風に乗り夜の淵へ
riding the wind to the edge of the night.
輝く月が
The shining moon
その横顔を捉える
captures that profile.
冷たく光る
Coldly glittering,
左手は何を掴む
what does the left hand grasp?
解れゆく世界の
Of the unraveling world,
欠片をひとひら
a single fragment.
意思の火を片手に
With the fire of will in one hand,
篝歩く
I walk with a watch-fire.
終わりなど見えない
Seeing no end in sight,
仕組みなのだから
since that's how it's designed.
問う事は諦め
Giving up on questioning,
一つ一つ
one by one...
終糸途切れ
The final thread breaks,
気付けば唯一の針
realizing it's the only needle.
縋る事さえ
Even clinging to something
許されずに膝を折る
is not allowed as I fall to my knees.
水面に映る
Reflected on the water's surface,
ツギハギだらけの身体
is a body full of patches.
空蝉に問う
I ask the empty shell,
これは夢か幻か
is this a dream or an illusion?
くたびれては眠り
Growing weary and sleeping,
赤い夢を見る
I dream a red dream.
篝火は倒れて 空を焦がす
The bonfire has fallen and scorched the sky
急き立てられるように ゆらり歩き出す
As if being hurried, I begin to walk swayingly
孤独な太陽の様に 繰り返して
Like a lonely sun, repeating...
繋ぎ止める
Tie it down
全ての火を
All the fires
澄み切った青空 岩陰にもたれて
A clear blue sky, leaning against the shadow of a rock
頬撫でゆく風は 「おやすみ」と呟いた
The wind caressing my cheek whispered "Good night"
解れ 解れ 欠片に戻る 現世の記憶は
Unravel, unravel, return to fragments, the memories of this world
霧散の瀬戸際を 未だ見ず
Still not seeing the brink of scattering
辛うじて留める 形を繋ぐ 敢え無い魔法は
Barely holding on, connecting the forms, the fleeting magic
掛け替えの無い 命の影
The shadow of an irreplaceable life
動かぬその右手には クチナシの花束を
In that unmoving right hand, a bouquet of gardenias
地に還る魂に 捧ぐ花向け
A floral tribute dedicated to the soul returning to the earth
残された世界には 縁なしの絶望と
In the remaining world, there is bottomless despair and...
願わくば暫くの 永遠を
If I may wish, for a temporary eternity
昔々あるところに、とても素晴らしい魔法の王国がありました。
Once upon a time, in a certain place, there was a very wonderful magical kingdom.
しかし、その王国は争い事に負けてしまい世界から消え、雪の中に埋もれてしまいました。
However, that kingdom lost a war and disappeared from the world, buried under the snow.
それから数百年、１人の白キツネの子がこの荒廃した地を訪れ、自分の国を作りたいと願いました。
Hundreds of years later, a white fox child visited this devastated land and wished to build their own country.
争い事の無い輝かしい王国を…もう一度…と。
A brilliant kingdom without conflict... once more...
吹き荒ぶ風に舞う 光追いかけて
Chasing the light that dances in the blowing wind
辿り着いた昔の王国
I arrived at an ancient kingdom
あぁ...
Aa...
飛び交う竜の面影が　滑る大地を
The shadows of flying dragons glide across the earth
「未来」で遺跡だった塔が　見下ろす
The tower that was a ruin in the "future" looks down
幼い頃から好きな古書に
In the old book I've loved since I was small
書かれた伝承が私の目の前に広がる
The legend written there unfolds before my eyes
遥か彼方を行く翼に　手を振り
Waving my hand to the wings going far away
空を映した瞳を見開く
Opening wide the eyes that reflected the sky
遠い景色に懐かしさを　覚えて
Feeling nostalgia in the distant scenery
耳に似た旋律を　ふと口ずさむ
I suddenly hum a melody similar to what I hear
澄み渡る湖に鱗が　跳ねれば
If scales splash in the crystal-clear lake
水泡が光を浴び　煌めく
Water bubbles catch the light and sparkle
振り向いた夕焼けに並んだ　影は
The shadows lined up in the sunset I looked back at
飛竜の形に造られた　石像
Are stone statues made in the shape of wyverns
禁忌を願った竜の運命
The fate of the dragon who wished for the taboo
身体は石となり魂を　閉じ込め
Body turning to stone, trapping the soul
神の掟に私はただ　震えて
I only tremble at the law of God
何もできずに唇を　噛んだ
Biting my lip, unable to do anything
指で触れても鉄のように　冷たいだけで
Even if I touch it with my finger, it's just cold as iron
届かない竜の心に
To the unreachable heart of the dragon
悪い予感が過る胸を　誤魔化し
Deceiving my heart where a bad premonition crosses
星を映した瞳を閉じた
Closing the eyes that reflected the stars
不意に零れた　その涙の理由さえ知らず
Not even knowing the reason for those tears that suddenly spilled
陽は沈み大地は眠りに　落ちる
The sun sets and the earth falls into slumber
安らかに...
Peacefully...
白狐の子狐の歌の魔法が雪を溶かし、
The fox magic of the white fox cub's song melted the snow,
その声に、夢に惹かれた者たちが「一緒に」と手を差し出しました。
and at that voice, those drawn by dreams reached out their hands, saying, "Let's be together."
どんどん国に暖かな灯が灯り始め、希望に溢れる街が生まれました。
Warm lights began to flicker one after another throughout the land, and a city filled with hope was born.
その眩い光景に白い狐の子は過去と、そして、これからの未来に思いを馳せるのでした。
In that dazzling sight, the little white fox would reflect on the past and, then, the future to come.
これからの未来に思いを馳せるのでした。
She was thinking about the future to come.
本日は、フブキングダム・プロローグにお越しくださりありがとうございます！
Thank you all for coming to FBKingdom Prologue today!
うわー！
Whoo!
皆さん見てください、後ろ！
Everyone, look behind me!
なんかでっかいのが建ってる！
There's something huge built back there!
もしや、これはフブキングダムのお城が？
Could this be the FBKingdom castle?
ちょっとずつちょっとずつ出来上がってるってこと？
Does this mean it's being built bit by bit?
わーい！
Yay!
ちょっと今までね、フブキングダム結構曖昧なところがあり、皆がダンボールに住んでたりなどなどしてきましたけども、
Until now, FBKingdom has been a bit vague, with everyone living in cardboard boxes and such,
ついに今日、もしがすると立派なお城が建つのかな？どうかな？
but finally today, maybe a grand castle will be built? What do you think?
ここから始まるフブキングダム、ちょっと皆さんお楽しみにしてください！
Please look forward to the FBKingdom that starts from here!
そして本日の生誕のハッシュタグなんですけども、皆さん、
And as for today's birthday hashtag, everyone...
フブキングダムプロローグとなっておりまーす！
it's FBKingdom Prologue!
カタカナとね、英語、どっちでもオッケーということで、海外ニキは英語かな？と思っております。
Both Katakana and English are fine, so I think the overseas fans will probably use English.
まず１曲、２曲とちょっと続けてね、紙芝居なんかも挟みつつ、楽しんでいただけましたでしょうか？
Did you enjoy the first two songs and the picture story show that followed?
ここからはね、ちょっとダンスとかめちゃめちゃ頑張るパートなので、今から気合を入れていこうと思いまーす！
From here, it's a part where I'll be working really hard on dancing, so I'm going to psych myself up now!
たくさんたくさんスクショとか、ポストとかしてくださいね。よろしくお願いします！
Please take lots and lots of screenshots and make posts. Thank you!
では次の曲、行ってみましょう！
Now, let's head to the next song!
魔女と旋律の街
作詞・作曲・Fly
The Witch and the City of Melody
Lyrics/Composition: Fly
宵の街 照らす灯火
A lamp illuminating the evening town
高らかに 響く旋律
A melody echoing loudly
月明かり 背に受けながら
While bathing in the moonlight from behind
独り 魔女は歌う
Alone, the witch sings
少女はためらう 目的地見出せずに
The girl hesitates, unable to find her destination
杖を掲げた まだ見ぬ明日へ向かって
She raised her staff, toward the unseen tomorrow
鐘の音がこだましようとも
Even if the sound of bells echoes
この世界で 魔女にはなれない
In this world, she cannot become a witch
空とたゆたう 旋律
A melody swaying with the sky
誓いさえ 風に吹かれて
Even her oath is blown by the wind
広場に繋がる 路地裏
An alleyway leading to the square
そのゆえ 時計台上見上げて
For that reason, looking up at the clock tower
石畳 独り佇む
Standing alone on the cobblestones
影を落とす少女
The girl casting a shadow
自らの呪縛で
By her own curse
自ら 苛み続ける
She continues to torment herself
例え手を差し伸べようとも 解けはしないでしょう
Even if you reach out a hand, it won't be undone
かつてあるものの 凋落で
With the decline of what once was
国は滅びて
The nation perishes
物語を紐解こうとも
Even if I unraveled the story
私はまだ君に学べない
I still haven't learned from you
望まれるように 演じる
Playing the part as desired
役割は日々ゆらめいて
The role fluctuates day by day
願いと祈りのメモリア
A memorial of wishes and prayers
鐘の音がこだましようとも
Even if the sound of bells echoes
この世界で 魔女にはなれない
In this world, she cannot become a witch
空とたゆたう 旋律
A melody swaying with the sky
誓いさえ 風に吹かれて
Even her oath is blown by the wind
物語を紐解こうとも
Even if I unraveled the story
私はまだ君に学べない
I still haven't learned from you
薄氷照らす 朝日に
In the morning sun illuminating thin ice
答えを探しに旅立とう
Let's set out on a journey to find the answer
さあさあこの指にとまれ
Come on, come on, stop at this finger
後悔後でしても知らないぞ
Don't blame me if you regret it later
音に呑まれて　歌って踊って満たすだけ
Just get swallowed by the sound, sing, dance, and satisfy yourself
パンパン手を打ち鳴らして
Clap, clap, sound out your hands
ソッソッソラシドどんな五線譜も
So, so, so-la-si-do, no matter the staff
音色を落として　今導き出すよ
Drop the timbre and I'll lead the way now
正体は実は案外はがゆいもの
The true identity is actually surprisingly frustrating
魔法のタクト空に翳すだけ
Just hold the magic baton up to the sky
おいであ
Come here
街を包み込んだ超常現象が
The paranormal phenomenon that enveloped the city
夜空に、ほらこだまして退屈が泣き出す
Is echoing in the night sky, look, boredom starts to cry
孤独な愛を埋めよう最終妄想的ノクターンが
Let's fill the lonely love, the final delusional nocturne
君は聞こえた？星に舞う旋律を
Did you hear it? The melody dancing in the stars
ワンツースリーしで泣いてた過去に負けない巡る力を
One-two-three-four, the power that goes around, not losing to the past that was crying
楽しいリズムで途切れない音を乗せて
With a fun rhythm, carry the non-stop sound
タッタッ
Tattan
アイダイを描こうセプテット
Let's draw 'Idai', Septet
忘れてた景色の向こうのその向こう
Beyond the scenery you forgot, and even further
見て調和の綻び
Look at the rift in harmony
モノクロの望遠鏡
A monochrome telescope
待ったなしのぶっつけ本番で
No waiting, straight into the real performance
奏でよう
Let's play
理想輝く幻想的進行で
With a fantastic progression where ideals shine
いつも目が合うアイツと手を繋ぎ踊ろう
Let's hold hands and dance with that person who I always lock eyes with
何度も泣いて描いた心のエレジーを
The elegy of the heart drawn after crying many times
僕は聞こえただから今ここにいるんだ
I heard it, that's why I'm here now
正体は実は案外悲しいもの
The true identity is actually surprisingly sad
魔法の音色空に響かせて
Make the magic timbre resound in the sky
おいでよ
Come here
街を包み込んだ超常現象が
The paranormal phenomenon that enveloped the city
夜空に、ほらこだまして退屈が泣き出す
Is echoing in the night sky, look, boredom starts to cry
愉快な歌を歌おう最終演奏アンサンブルを
Let's sing a pleasant song, the final performance ensemble
君は聞こえた？星に舞う旋律を
Did you hear it? The melody dancing in the stars
ワンツースリーしで泣いて過去に負けない巡る力を
One-two-three-four, crying, the power that goes around, not losing to the past
楽しいリズムで途切れない音に乗せて
With a fun rhythm, carry the non-stop sound
タッタッ
Tattan
パンパン手を打ち鳴らして
Clap, clap, sound out your hands
踊れ踊れオーケストラ
Dance, dance, orchestra
バイバイ今夜はさよなら
Bye-bye, tonight is farewell
次は君もステージで
Next time, you'll be on stage too
タッタッ
Tattan
さあさあこの指にとまれ
Come on, come on, stop at this finger
後悔後でしても知らないぞ
Don't blame me if you regret it later
耳をすまして僕らと踊るだけ
Just listen closely and dance with us
Justice is still in my heart
君に届けユースティティア
Reaching out to you, Justitia
暗闇が立ち込めた様な　見捨てられた街で
In a deserted city that seemed to be shrouded in darkness
暗闇かき込めた様な 見捨てられた街で
In a forsaken town, as if filled with darkness,
命のユースティティア
Inochi no Justitia
一人 孤独を唄う君を見た
I saw you singing of solitude alone.
甦る過去 [kioku] に 魂霊して
As memories of the past echo back,
君の腕を掴む
I grab your arm.
ここが 約束の地だと信じて
Believing that this is the promised land.
確かな答えは 何処にも無いけれど
Though a definite answer is nowhere to be found,
籠の中の小鳥は 目覚めた
The little bird inside the cage has awakened.
羽ばたき無いまま 鼓動は加速して
With no wings to flap, the heartbeat accelerates.
僕らこの日を
We've been waiting for this day,
この時を待ち続けていたんだ
Waiting for this very moment.
叶わぬ祈りに 救いの両手を
To the prayers that won't come true, reach out with saving hands.
生まれ変われ 命のユースティティア
Be reborn, Justitia of Life.
どんな風 吹いていたって
No matter what kind of wind is blowing,
この声は 消せやしない
This voice cannot be silenced.
未来 [unmei] の僕らに 残せる物は何？
What can we leave for our future selves?
宙を照らせ 一縷のユースティティア
Light up the sky, a single ray of Justitia.
一秒だって 狂わせない
I won't let even a single second be out of sync.
奪われた世界を さあ 取り戻せ
Now, let's take back the world that was stolen.
重なり合って いつの日だって 僕らは共鳴している
Overlapping together, every single day, we are resonating.
錆び付いた扉に手かざして
Placing a hand on the rusted door,
再び描く現在
Painting the present once more.
君の 君だけの物語 [uta] が始まる
Your story, yours alone, begins.
失くした言葉と 言葉の意味を紡ぎ合わせて
Spinning together the lost words and their meanings,
強く 誰より力強く 咲き誇るその音を
Strongly, more powerfully than anyone, let that sound bloom in full glory.
どうか 絶やさないで
Please, don't ever let it die out.
僕が僕らしくあること
That I stay true to myself,
君が君らしくあること
That you stay true to yourself,
それが 果てしない僕らの ユースティティア
That is our endless Justitia.
叶わぬ祈りに 救いの両手を
To the prayers that won't come true, reach out with saving hands.
生まれ変われ 命のユースティティア
Be reborn, Justitia of Life.
どんな風 吹いていたって
No matter what kind of wind is blowing,
この声は 消せやしない
This voice cannot be silenced.
未来 [unmei] の僕らに 残せる物は何？
What can we leave for our future selves?
宙を照らせ 一縷のユースティティア
Light up the sky, a single ray of Justitia.
一秒だって 狂わせない
I won't let even a single second be out of sync.
奪われた世界を さあ 取り戻せ
Now, let's take back the world that was stolen.
信じ合って 騙されたって それでもそっと 光は降って
Even if we trust and are deceived, even so, the light gently falls.
いつかはきっと 必ずきっと
Someday for sure, definitely for sure,
僕が君の心 燈すから
Because I will light up your heart.
GATE～それは暁のように～
作詞・作曲・編曲：岸田
GATE ~Sore wa Akatsuki no You ni~
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Kishida
特に 何も望むことなんてない
There's nothing in particular that I wish for.
身の程は 知っているさ
I know my place.
そんな 僕でさえも奥の方に
Even in the depths of someone like me,
譲りたくない意向程度はあるらしい
There seems to be at least some resolve I won't yield.
守るって 案外と難しいね
Protecting something is unexpectedly difficult, isn't it?
諦めるわけじゃないけど
It's not that I'm giving up, though.
蒼い 空の果て 繋がった道の行方
At the end of the blue sky, the destination of the connected path.
人と人は分かち合えない
People can't understand each other
だけどいいんじゃない？
But isn't that okay?
開いた扉は全てを変えてゆく
The opened door will change everything
それは暁のように
Just like the break of dawn
何かを害することくらい
Harming something or other
誰にでも起こり得るだろう
Could happen to anyone, right?
何かを愛することなんて
Loving something...
もっと単純な話だと思えてきたから
I've started to think it's a much simpler matter
自分に返ってくる対価を
The price that comes back to you
期待したりしない　そんなのするだけ虚さ
Don't expect it, doing so is just empty
重要なのはひとつ　それをやりたいかどうかだけなんだ
Only one thing is important: whether you want to do it or not
（ねぇ）だって君はここに一人しかいない
(Hey) Because there's only one of you here
蒼い空の中　守るべきモノがある
In the blue sky, there's something to protect
それはどんな世界で生きるかより大切だから
Because that's more important than what kind of world you live in
開いた扉の先に何があっても
No matter what lies beyond the opened door
迷ってしまわないように
So that you don't get lost
大体の場合えらい奴は　仕様ならないけど
In most cases, the big shots are useless
必要があるなら　仕方ないと思えなくもない
But if it's necessary, I can't say I don't think it's unavoidable
ならやるべきことは分かりきってるはずさ
Then what needs to be done should be obvious
それくらいのやる気はあるだろう？
You've got that much motivation, right?
蒼い空が割れ　夢と現実が混ざる
The blue sky cracks, dream and reality mix
人と人は分かち合えない　そんな場合じゃない
It's not the time to say people can't understand each other
開いた扉は全てを変えてゆく
The opened door will change everything
それは暁のように
Just like the break of dawn
はい！ということで！みなさーん！新衣装でーす！イエーイ！
Yes! So! Everyone! Here's my new outfit! Yay!
そしてそして、フブキングダム、開城ー！ドドーン！うわー！
And also, Fubuki Kingdom, open for business! Ta-da! Wow!
すごい立派なお城が、いやいや我々の、お家が、できましたー！イエーイ！もう！
A magnificent castle, no, our home, is complete! Yay! Man!
そして国旗も旗めいておる！うおー！
And the national flag is waving too! Whoa!
いや、ちょっと、いいじゃないですか！王様らしく、なりましたよねー？ねー！？
Man, isn't it great? I look like a king now, right? Right!?
ゲストのみなとね、まぁゲストというか、この国を一緒に作り上げてくれた
Singing with the guests... well, not just guests, but the Holo-members
ホロメンたちと一緒に歌いつつ、
who helped build this country together...
そしてね、ステージの前にいる、ドムのみんなの力で、こんなに立派なお城ができました。
And with the power of all the Domu in front of the stage, we were able to build such a grand castle.
そして後で、一旗置いとこうかな、よいしょ。こちらの、衣装名は「聖（セイント）衣装」となっております！
And later, let me put a flag here. This outfit is called the "Saint Costume"!
ちょっと、みなさんに、じっくり、見てもらいたいので、ぐるぐるーっと、ぐるぐるーっと。
I want everyone to take a good look, so let's spin around, and around.
はい、いろんなね、この頭の王冠のところとかにも、なんと！金木犀が回っておりまして！
Yes, even on the crown on my head, look! Fragrant olives are spinning!
白上の大好きな、お花の金木犀が、もう、いっぱい、いっぱい、入ってる衣装となっておりまーす！
This outfit is full of fragrant olives, Shirakami's favorite flower!
そしてですね、なんとこの、衣装なんですけど、王冠が、たぶん外れるかな？王冠も取れちゃうのかな？どうだよ。
And also, with this outfit, I think the crown can be removed? Can the crown be taken off? Let's see.
いけますかー？ぽい。あ、消えた消えた。そしてたぶんね、マントも、このケープもきっと、消えるかな？どうかな。
Ready? Poof. Oh, it's gone. And maybe the cloak, this cape will probably disappear too? Let's see.
わあ！
Whoa!
できたー！あーよかった！
I did it! Ah, thank goodness!
こんな感じ、ちょっとねラフな格好にもなるんですね。
Like this, it can also be a bit of a casual look.
うわあー！
Wow!
そしてこのふわふわのケモノの毛。
And these fluffy animal ears.
ふわふわふわふわ。
Fluffy, fluffy.
良くないですか？
Isn't it great?
かわちい。
Cute.
とってもとっても、えー可愛いお洋服を作っていただきました、ありがとうございます！
They made such a very, very cute outfit for me, thank you!
そしてなんか後ろのこの石像。
And this stone statue in the back.
スコーン部に石像職人の方がいらっしゃいました。
There was a stone statue craftsman in the Scone Club.
なんかフブラがいるんですよ。
Look, Fubura is here.
なんかお前の城みたいになってるけど違うからなお前！
It looks like it's your castle, but you're wrong!
これは我々のお城だ！
This is our castle!
ね、フブラじゃないですからね。
Right? It's not Fubura's.
もう、わかってますか皆さん。
Seriously, do you guys understand?
ね、ちょっとスクショも撮ってもらおうかな。ピース！
I'll let you take some screenshots. Peace!
こんピース！
Kon-Peace!
いえいいえいいえい！いえいいえいいえい！
Yay, yay, yay! Yay, yay, yay!
おー照れるなーこんなにかわちい衣装。
Oh, I'm getting shy with such a cute outfit.
ね、なんと、えーまあ色々これまでね、あのアイドル衣装とかブルジャニとかありましたけども。
Well, so far, you know, I've had various things like idol outfits and Blue Journey...
白上のこの単独の3D衣装というのは実は初めてですね。
But this is actually the first solo 3D outfit for Shirakami.
初めてなので、すごいなんか緊張がすごいですけども。
Since it's the first one, I'm really nervous.
きっとみんなね、すごい盛り上がってくれてありがとう。ありがとうございます。
Thank you all for getting so excited. Thank you so much.
えー、ではですね、えーちょっと衣装のお披露目もそこそこに、次の曲も行ってみようと思います。
Well then, now that the outfit reveal is mostly done, I'll move on to the next song.
さて、建国後のフブキングダム。
Now, for the FBKingdom after its founding.
まだまだ、これから続いていくぞー！
It's still going to continue from here on!
時は今！
The time is now!
時は今！ようやく手にしたのは夢のぐだふぁ生活
The time is now! Finally, I've got my dreamy, lazy life.
やっと手にしたのは夢のぐだふぁ生活！
Finally, I've got my dreamy, lazy life!
瀟洒な屋敷日々を誰にも邪魔されずに満喫したい
I want to enjoy every day in this elegant mansion without being disturbed.
ああそれなのに！
Ah, and yet!
ああそれなのに！立ちはだかるトラブルまたトラブル！
Ah, and yet! Troubles standing in my way, and more troubles!
立ちはだかるトラブル！またトラブル！
Troubles standing in my way! And more troubles!
だがそれでも諦めない！
But still, I won't give up!
だがそれでも諦めない！夢に描いた悠々自適生活を取り戻すまでは！
But still, I won't give up! Until I get back the leisurely life of my dreams!
夢に描いた悠々自適生活を取り戻すまでは！
Until I get back the leisurely life of my dreams!
ぐだぐだぐだしていたいの　全人類共通項
I want to be lazy, lazy, lazy—a common trait for all humanity
ぐだぐだぐだしたい
I want to be lazy, lazy, lazy
全人類共通項
Common trait for all humanity
食う、寝る、あと何だっけ？
Eat, sleep, and what else?
食う・寝る・あと何だっけ？？？
Eat, sleep, and what else???
あーあー聞こえないです
Ah, I can't hear you!
ヤダヤダもう邪魔しないで　とっておきスローライフ
No, no, don't disturb me—my special slow life
ヤダヤダもう邪魔しないで
No, no, don't disturb me
とっておきスローライフ
My special slow life
やりたいことだけやって生きていたいわ
I just want to live doing only what I want to do
やりたいことだけ
Only what I want to do
やって生きていたいわ
I want to live doing it
しかし穏やかな生活を目指そうとしてもまるで荒波のように次々と困難は襲いかかってくるのです！
However, even if I try to lead a peaceful life, difficulties attack one after another like rough waves!
しかし穏やかな生活を目指そうとしても
However, even if I try to lead a peaceful life
次々と困難は襲いかかってくるのです！
Difficulties attack one after another!
静々太平我が家の安寧
Quietly peaceful, the serenity of my home
兎にも角にも安らぎ重視で平穏無事に暮らしていたい！
Anyway, prioritizing peace, I want to live in tranquility!
叶えて私のHappy Days
Grant me my Happy Days
おはようからおやすみまでまるっと穏便に
Peacefully all the way from good morning to good night
余裕綽々杓子も猫も
Plenty of leeway, for everyone and their cat
ふわふわ沸いちゃうそんなEvery day
Such a fluffy, exciting everyday
晴耕雨読で心穏やかな暮らし
Living in harmony with nature, a heart-calming life
きっと手に入れてみせるわ！
I'll surely make it mine!
まだまだまだまだ足りないの　健康的市民生活
It's still, still, still not enough—a healthy civic life
ビタミン　ミネラル　精神的サプリメント
Vitamins, minerals, mental supplements
クラクラしちゃうこのクライシス　ラクラクに変える
Changing this dizzying crisis into something easy
そんな逆転劇　絶賛進行中
Such a reversal drama is currently in full swing
ぐだぐだするためにあくせくしなきゃいけないのってこれ本末転倒になっちゃってません？
Isn't it putting the cart before the horse if I have to work hard just to be lazy?
あ、これ気付いちゃダメなやつでした？気付かなかったことにしておきます！
Ah, was I not supposed to notice that? I'll pretend I didn't!
賢いことに越した事はないけど
It's better to be smart, but...
いつの時代も変わらないもの　寝ても覚めても癒されたい！
Somethings never change in any era—I want to be healed whether asleep or awake!
許して不純なAmbitious
Forgive my impure Ambitious
健康で文化的な最低限度のユートピア
A healthy and cultural minimum utopia
海千山千抜かりありません
Experienced and prepared for anything
ぐだぐだぐだなステージが欲しいから
Because I want a lazy, lazy stage
完全無欠で満ち足りた毎日を
A flawless and satisfying every day
お星さまにお祈りしよう
Let's pray to the stars
ぐだぐだふわり　ぐだぐだふわり　ぐだぐだふわり　ぐだぐだふわり
Lazy, fluffy, lazy, fluffy, lazy, fluffy, lazy, fluffy
叶えて私のHappy Life
Grant me my Happy Life
揺り籠から墓場まで健やかに
Healthy from the cradle to the grave
青息吐息　生きてゆくこと
Gasping for breath, going on living...
決して楽じゃない　けれど
It's never easy, however...
叶えて私の Happy Days
Make my Happy Days come true.
おはようから
From good morning
おやすみまでまるっと
To good night, all of it.
穏便に
Peacefully,
余裕綽々　杓子も猫も
With plenty of ease, everyone and their cat.
Fu Fu
Why do I そんな Every day
Fu Fu Why do I every day like that?
晴耕雨読で
Tilling in the sun and reading in the rain,
心穏やかな暮らし
A peaceful life.
手に入れるその日まで！！
Until the day I get my hands on it!!
Secret Garden
月夜のセレナーデ
A moonlit serenade.
白い薔薇は誰を想う
Who does the white rose long for?
その身を震わせて
Making its body tremble,
愛を歌うの
It sings of love.
零れ落ちた花びらが
The falling petals
寂しさの跡を隠した
Hid the traces of loneliness.
ねぇ早く
Hey, hurry up
(迎えに来て)
(And come pick me up),
最後のひとひらが落ちるその前に
Before the final petal falls.
今はどんな花とも群れないの
Now, I won't flock with any other flower.
あなただけを待ってる
I'm waiting only for you.
あなたとならこの身体が
If I'm with you, even if this body
壊されたってもう構わない
Is broken, I don't care anymore.
棘に触れたら
If you touch the thorns,
傷つくわ
You'll get hurt.
その覚悟がないなら
If you don't have that resolve,
いっそここから消えてよ
Then just disappear from here already.
重く閉ざしたそう
Closed tightly... yes,
Secret Garden
夜風はリゾルート
The night breeze is resolute.
白い薔薇は覚醒する
The white rose awakens.
背中押されるように
As if being pushed from behind,
扉開いた
The door opened.
ただ独りで枯れてゆくの？
Will you just wither away all alone?
待ってるだけじゃいられない
I can't just keep waiting.
衝動の赴くまま
Following my impulses,
茨の道を裸足で駆け抜けてく
I run through the path of thorns barefoot.
凛と咲き誇る華でありたい
I want to be a flower that blooms with dignity.
あなただけを求めて
Seeking only you.
会いに行くの
I'm going to see you,
どんな遠く離れていても見つけ出せる
No matter how far apart we are, I can find you.
暗い世界も怖くない
I'm not afraid of the dark world,
あなたを感じるから
Because I feel you.
全て失ったっていい
I don't mind losing everything.
二度と戻らないそう
I'll never return... yes,
Secret Garden
今はどんな花とも群れないの
Now, I won't flock with any other flower.
あなただけを求めて
Seeking only you.
霞の向こう　わたしを呼ぶ
From beyond the haze, you call to me.
鮮やかに燃える強き薔薇
A strong rose burning vividly.
凛と咲き誇る華でありたい
I want to be a flower that blooms with dignity.
やっとここで出逢えた
I finally met you here.
あなたとならこの身体が
If I'm with you, even if this body
壊されたってもう構わない
Is broken, I don't care anymore.
棘に触れたら
If you touch the thorns,
傷つくわ
You'll get hurt.
その覚悟があるのね
You have that resolve, don't you?
手を取り合えば広がる
If we hold hands, it will spread,
誰も知らないそう
Nobody knows... yes,
Sacred Universe
福音
Gospel
作詞・作曲：wotaku
Lyrics & Composition: wotaku
「間違っていないか その再現性を 関係を」
“Is it not wrong? That reproducibility... that relationship.”
「そうなっても何か 役に立つの？」
“Even so, will it be of any use?”
「夢なんか見ないで 戦争をしようよ」
“Don't dream. Let's start a war.”
瞑想も 読経も 笑って 嘆き合う者
Meditation, sutras... those who laugh and mourn together.
アンティークとなった 旧文明禁書 概要の
The summary of the prohibited books of an ancient civilization that became antiques.
8128項の内容
The contents of section 8128.
千変も時間も 空間もない方 信仰と
Towards those where there is no change, time, or space... faith and...
祈り その距離 救い出すもの
prayer. That distance, that which saves.
光よ 慈しみよ
O light, O compassion.
深き 尊き 汝の愛で
With your deep and noble love,
導きたまえ
Lead me.
穿たれた福音 下された御指 燻べた紫高に
The pierced gospel. The lowered finger. To the smoldering purple height.
灰になった権力者
The powerful ones who have turned to ash.
消え去ってく論理 知れば戻れぬ昨日に その量子
Logic that fades away. To the yesterday we can't return to once we know. That quantum.
悪を焼き去った 剣よ
O sword that burnt away evil.
焼かれた元老院 裸に剥かれた武器商人
The burnt Senate. The arms dealers stripped bare.
苛烈さを増す 学生達のテロ行為
Terrorist acts of students increasing in severity.
上から見ればエンナ 下から見ればホザンナ
From above, Gehenna. From below, Hosanna.
あぁ んな筈じゃなかった
Ah, it wasn't supposed to be like this.
奇跡よ 思し召しよ
O miracle, O divine will.
人を 気高き 窮理の船に乗せ
Take people on the noble ship of truth-seeking.
導きたまえ
Lead me.
つまんない
Boring.
Da-Da-Dura-Da-Dura-Dura
キャッシュー・ベスト・フレンド
Cash is my best friend.
クラブ＝マジェスティ
Club Majesty
作詞・作曲：Nyanyannya
Lyrics & Composition: Nyanyannya
あれもMoney これもMoney 多重債務の豚にゃ用なし
That's money, this is money. No use for pigs with multiple debts.
この先じゃハートはPricey 哀れ口先だけのゾンビもなっちゃ
Beyond here, hearts are pricey. Even a pitiful zombie who's all talk.
それにReady 惹かれディー 高貴な死の香りを纏って
Ready for that? Lured by 'D'. Wrapped in the scent of a noble death.
そこにキャッシュをお持ちなら 何なりとお望みを ハーマジェスティ
If you have cash there, tell me your wish, Her Majesty.
お迎えだ絢爛に 招待状 取引
A grand welcome. Invitation... transaction.
魂 売ったり買ったり 騙してそして騙されたり
Buying and selling souls. Deceiving and being deceived.
奪ったりもっと奪われたり 欲しいまま 欲しいまま
Taking and being taken from. Just as desired, just as desired.
ゼンブ？ ゼンゼンゼンゼンゼンブだ
Everything? All, all, all, all, all of it.
悦べ ゴージャスなドレス ゴージャスなリップ
Rejoice! Gorgeous dress, gorgeous lips.
あなたの地獄へ クラブ＝マジェスティ
To your hell, Club Majesty.
歓迎さ強欲の君 私はバトラー
Welcome, greedy one. I am the butler.
ドッペルもジーザスも 吊るなり 剥ぐなり 思い通り
Doppelgangers and Jesus... hang them or strip them as you wish.
ご用命はなぁに？
What is your order?
Da-Da-Dura-Da-Dura-Dura
キャッシュー・ベスト・フレンド
Cash is my best friend.
お星様の望むだけ 降り注ぐ銀貨に囲まれて 家族は幸せに暮らしましたー
As much as the stars wish, surrounded by pouring silver coins, the family lived happily ever after.
またのご冗談ばかり
You're joking again.
...いいんだよ精々
...It's fine, at best.
それがマネー　誰のマネー
That's money. Whose money?
百倍＆福利グレード
A hundred times & compound interest grade.
借りたら返すのが誠意でしょう？
If you borrow, you should pay it back.
Isn't that sincerity?
其の通りをサンキュー
Exactly, thank you.
おーシェイクハンズ
Oh, shake hands.
本日もようこそご案内ショウタイム
Welcome again today, guide showtime.
公平
Fairness.
魂売ったり買ったり
Selling and buying souls.
選んだりそして叶ったり
Choosing and then coming true,
奪ったりもっと奪ったり
taking and taking more.
止められない
Can't stop.
モット？モット！モット！さあ！
More? More! More! Now!
ウェルカム・トゥ・キラメキグラス
Welcome to Kirameki Glass,
奈落の聖域
sanctuary of the abyss.
クラブ＝マジェスティ
Club Majesty.
羨望も絶望もどこから受けましょう
From where shall we receive envy and despair?
どうぞアナタがルール
Please, you are the rule.
知らないだけフール
You're just a fool who doesn't know.
弱虫な貴方資格してあげる
I'll give you a coward's qualification.
さっさと再燃して
Burn up quickly.
キャッシュはホワイトナイト
Cash is a white knight.
絶体絶命で取引
A deal in a desperate situation.
魂売ったり買ったり
Selling and buying souls.
選んだりそして叶ったり
Choosing and then coming true,
奪ったりもっと奪ったり
taking and taking more.
足りない
Not enough.
チョット？チョット！チョット！
A little? A little! A little!
モット？モット！ゼンブ？ゼンブ！オールライト！
More? More! All? All! All right!
もしかして愛だとか　情だとか
Could it be that you believe in fake things
紛い物信じていらっしゃる？
like love or affection?
裏切らないのはやっぱり金でしょ？
What doesn't betray you is money, right?
ふさわしきも　お洒落にも
Both suitable and stylish,
瞬き一文字で命がないのさ
there's no life in a blink of a character.
痛い痛い愛の慈しみを　憎しみを
The painful, painful affection of love, the hatred,
あなたの地獄へ
into your hell.
クラブ＝マジェスティ
Club Majesty.
豊かになれる万能エネルギー
Universal energy that can make you rich.
心ゆくまでお楽しみいただけましたでしょうか？
I hope you enjoyed yourself to your heart's content.
キャッシュは惜しまない
Don't spare the cash.
イッツショウタイム！
It's showtime!
キャッシュはベストフレンド
Cash is a best friend.
きらりと輝く言葉
I kept searching for
僕は探し続けた
words that shine brightly.
色褪せる時間にさえ
I didn't even notice
気づかないでいた
the time fading away.
流れゆく星のように
If I could fly across this night sky
この夜空を飛べたなら
like a shooting star.
君に伝えたい声も
I wonder if the voice I want to convey
輝けるのかな
to you could also shine.
掴んだヒカリ
The light I grabbed.
解き放つオト
The sound released.
魔法をかけてよ
Cast a spell on me.
METEOR
この空を　あの星を
Across this sky, those stars,
奇跡さえ超えて君の元へ
even beyond miracles, to you.
繋げるよ　その夢を
I'll connect that dream,
最後まで離さないで
so don't let go until the end.
この歌を　この声を
Please never forget
ずっと忘れないでいてね
this song, this voice.
届けたい　終わりのない空を
I want to deliver the melody of stars
翔ける星のメロディ
soaring through the endless sky.
きらりと果てのない道を
The starlight illuminating
照らしてくスターライト
the endless path.
何も見えないけれど
I can't see anything,
僕は進んでゆく
but I'll keep going.
透き通る風のように
If I could fly through this night sky
この夜空を飛べたなら
like a transparent breeze.
砂にまみれた声も
I wonder if the voice covered
また光れるのかな
in sand can shine again.
口ずさんだ
I hummed.
そのメロディに
To that melody.
魔法をかけてよ
Cast a spell on me.
METEOR
君の書く　その歌は
The song you write becomes
無数の光る言葉となって
countless shining words.
目を覚ます　この声と
With this voice that wakes up,
シグナルが青に染まる
the signal turns blue.
これからも　この先も
From now on and in the future,
僕は君を振り返らせる
I'll make you look back.
笑って　笑って飛ばせ
Smile, smile and fly away,
笑顔よ咲け明日へ
let your smile bloom towards tomorrow.
願いを託す時間を止めてよ
Stop the time entrusted with wishes.
鳴り止まない鼓動ハイスピード
The unstoppable heartbeat at high speed.
無限に続くような銀河さえ
Even the galaxy that seems to
魔法に溶けてゆく
last forever melts into magic.
ココロの中に星を降らせるよ
I'll make stars fall into your heart
しっかりと受け止めて欲しいんだ
I want you to catch them firmly
君に伝えたいこの歌を今
This song I want to convey to you now
全力で歌っているから
I'm singing it with all my might
この空を　あの星を
This sky, that star
奇跡さえ超えて君の元へ
I'll cross even miracles to reach you
飛べるよ　どこまでも
I can fly anywhere
今ならきっと大丈夫
I'm sure it's okay now
この歌は　その声は
This song, that voice
いつも君の隣にある
Is always by your side
届けたい　終わりのない空を
I want to reach the endless sky
翔ける星のメロディ
A melody of soaring stars
巡り合う　この場所で
Meeting in this place
君と二人の夜空を見る
I watch the night sky with you
駆け出して　それだけで
Just by starting to run
きっと夢は叶うから
I'm sure the dream will come true
この歌を　この声を
This song, this voice
ずっと忘れないでいてね
Please don't ever forget
届けたい　遥か遠い未来
I want to reach the distant future
駆け抜ける　全速力のメロディ
A melody running through at full speed
はい、ということで、METEOR聴いていただきましてありがとうございました。
Yes, and so, thank you very much for listening to METEOR.
や、もう、ふぅー、やばかった！
Wow, whew, that was amazing!
いや、もう今回の曲ね、ちょっとゆったりから始まり、
No, this song today, you know, it starts off a bit relaxed,
えー、なかなか激しい曲ときて、そして高い曲とね、
and then comes a quite intense part, and then a high-pitched part,
後半になるにつれ、ちょっと、あの、激しい感じにはなっていってるんですけどもね、
as it gets towards the second half, it gets a bit of an intense feeling, though.
今回のちょっと曲順とか、あの、なんでこういうセットリストなのかっていうのはまた、あの、後日お話しできたらと思います。
Regarding today's song order and why the setlist is like this, I'd like to talk about that another day.
そして！
And!
なんと、後ろ！なんかおるんですけど、おーい！
Somehow, behind me! There's something there, hey!
ふぶら！ちょっと！
Fubura! Wait a minute!
お前、侵略しに来たのか？
Did you come to invade?
え、違うのかな？守護神ってこと？フブキングダムの。
Eh, maybe not? Are you the guardian deity of Fubukin Kingdom?
そうなのかな？えー、ちょっとあの、すこん部の中で、あの、国民の皆さんで、あの、
Is that so? Well, among the Sukon-bu, among all the citizens,
ふぶら飼育係募集しております。あの、よろしくお願いいたします。
we are recruiting Fubura caretakers. Please lend us your help.
そうですね、ここからは、告知を2つ、ちょっと、えー、やっていこうかなと思います。
Right, from here, I'm thinking of doing two announcements.
ではでは。ふぅー。
Well then. Whew.
まず1つ目は、こちら！
First, here's the first one!
白上フブキ 生誕記念2024グッズです！わー！
Shirakami Fubuki Birthday Celebration 2024 merchandise! Yay!
誕生記念2024
Birthday Commemoration 2024
ではではでは、早速どんなグッズがあるのか見ていきましょう。まず1つ目は、こちら！
Well then, let's take a look at what kind of merchandise there is. First, here it is!
タイトルがかっこよすぎる、「黄昏の王」アクリルスタンドです！
The title is too cool, the 'King of Twilight' acrylic stand!
今回ね、さっきあの、衣装の、あの、見てもらったときにこちらの衣装、セイント衣装って紹介したんですけど、
This time, earlier when I showed you the outfit, I introduced this one as the Saint outfit,
実はですね、今回のこのグッズのイラストを担当してくださっているげぜるん先生が、こちらの衣装のデザインもしてくださいました！
actually, Gezerun-sensei, who is in charge of the illustrations for this merchandise, also designed this outfit!
本当に、本当にいつもありがとうございます。えー、そんなげぜるん先生が、
Really, thank you very much as always. So, Gezerun-sensei,
もう、やっぱもう衣装詳しいので、もう、今回のグッズもお願いしますと、お願いして、えー、描いていただきました。
since they're so familiar with the outfit, I asked them to do the merchandise as well, and they drew it for me.
と、「黄昏の王」ということで、なんか背景のこのステンドグラスとかもフブキングダムイメージして作っていただきました。とってもとっても可愛いアクリルスタンドです。
And since it's 'King of Twilight', the stained glass in the background was also made with Fubukin Kingdom in mind. It's a very, very cute acrylic stand.
では、続いてはこちら！
Now, next is this!
缶バッジ！もうね、お顔が本当に、本当に、かわちかわちなの！缶バッジもお願いさせていただきました。
Button badge! The face is really, really so cute! I also asked for a button badge.
こちらなんとですね、あの、ジュエリー箔？というですね、ぷっくり立体的な、なんとですね、箔押しがついてるんですよ。
This one actually has, what's it called, jewelry foil? It's like a puffy, three-dimensional foil stamping.
もうね、高級感も抜群なので、ぜひぜひ推しバ作って、くれると嬉しいです。
It feels very high-end, so I'd be happy if you'd make an oshi-bag with it.
では続いてはこちら！わー！きちゃ！
Now, next is this! Whoa! Here it is!
白上、あの、個人的に、おし、ぬいを作るんですけども、その時にいつも作っている、あの、お顔があるんですけど、
Personally, I make plushies, and there's a certain face I always use when I do,
そのお顔でなんと今回ぬいを、作っちゃいました！
and with that face, I've actually made a plushie this time!
SUKONBU FACTORY Vol.1 セイントフブちゃんぬいぐるみ！
SUKONBU FACTORY Vol.1 Saint Fubu-chan Plushie!
ということで！
And so!
お待たせいたしました！
Sorry for the wait!
もうね、これVol.1ということで、もしかすると今後も作っていけるのかな...
Since this is Vol. 1, I made it with the hope that I might be able to continue making more...
...という期待を込めてVol.1にさせていただきました。
...in the future.
ね！こちらの、お顔でね、今後も何か作っていけたらいいな。
Right! I'd love to make more things with this face.
ぜひぜひ、白上がデザインさせていただいたぬい...
This plushie was designed by me, and the management team made it look really nice...
...を、運営さんが本当に良い感じに、あの、してくださったぬいとなっておりますので...
...so please welcome it into your home!
...お迎えよろしくお願いします！
Thank you!
そして続いてはこちら！デン！
And next is this! Bam!
フブキングダム勲章ピンバッジ！イエーイ！
Fubukungdom Order Medal Pin Badge! Yay!
この勲章をどうしてもグッズにしたかった。
I really wanted to turn this medal into merchandise.
前にね、あの出した、あのフブちゃんフェアのね、あのバッグにも、あのこの勲章のチャームが付いてるんですけども...
The Fubu-chan Fair bag I released before had a charm of this medal...
...あの、もっと、もっと大きく、ね、みんなに付けてほしいということで...
...but I wanted it to be bigger so everyone could wear it...
...こちらのね、勲章ピンバッジ作らせていただきました。
...so I made this pin badge.
お洋服にでももちろん付けるのもいいんですけども...
You can put it on your clothes, of course...
...ま、カバンとかにね、付けて一緒に国民アピールをしていただければと思います。
...but you can also put it on your bag to show off that you're a citizen.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you!
そして、フルセット購入特典もございます。
Also, there's a full set purchase bonus.
こちらのポストカードです。
It's this postcard.
数量限定バージョン、直筆サインもございます。
There's also a limited edition version with a handwritten signature.
年に一回の直筆サイン。頑張りと頑張りたいと思います、ってなんだ、頑張ろうと思います。
A once-a-year handwritten signature. I'll work hard— wait, I'll give it my all.
もうダメだ。口が回らへん。
I'm losing it. I'm tongue-tied.
頑張りますので、ぜひぜひ皆さんよろしくお願いいたします。
I'll do my best, so please support me.
さらに！フルセット特典として...
Furthermore! As a full set bonus...
Hololive Official Card Gameで使用できるカードが1枚付いてきます！
You'll get one card that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game!
こちらもよろしくお願いしますよ！
Please check this out too!
このあと、カートオープンです。わーわー！
The cart opens after this. Yay!
ということでね、今回もね、あの本当に色々考えてグッズ出させていただきました。
I put a lot of thought into the merchandise this time too.
運営さんに「これでお願いします、これでお願いします」と言って...
I told the staff "Please do this, please do that," and...
デザイこんなのですとかね、本当にいっぱい相談に乗っていただきありがとうございました。
We discussed the design a lot. Thank you so much for your help.
え、すこん部ファクトリーの工場で働いてるすこん部の皆さんはね...
To all the Sukonbu working at the Sukonbu Factory...
あの生産頑張ってください。よろしくお願いします。
Please do your best with production. Thank you.
そして、告知。二つ目！
And now, for the second announcement!
なんと、このあと歌う曲...新曲です！にゃー！
The song I'm about to sing... is a new song! Nyaa!
もうね、『レター』に続く、もう新曲も白上自身...
Following 'Letter,' this new song is also very 'Fubuki-ish.'
本当に『レター』がめちゃめちゃもうわー、白上ーって感じの曲なんですけど...
'Letter' was very much a 'Yay, Fubuki!' kind of song, but...
このね、次に歌わせていただく曲、「SUPERNOVA」という楽曲なんですけども...
...this next song, 'SUPERNOVA,' is a bit different.
またね、『レター』とは違った、あの白上とすこん部の関係というか...
It shows a different side of the relationship between Fubuki and the Sukonbu...
ね、さらにさらにさらに盛り上がる楽曲となっております。
...and it's a song that gets more and more exciting.
ちょっとね、皆さん初見なので、いきなり合いの手とかは難しいとは思うんですけども...
Since it's everyone's first time hearing it, call-and-response might be hard...
ちょっと覚えてね、またいつかね、こういうライブやるときに「イエイ！イエイ！」って盛り上がってくれると嬉しいなっていう...
...but please try to remember it so we can shout 'Yeah! Yeah!' together at future lives.
そういう一緒に、本当に一緒に盛り上がれる曲となっておりますので、ぜひぜひ聴いてください。
It's a song we can truly enjoy together, so please listen to it.
そして、この配信後に、MVも公開します！
Also, the music video will be released after this stream!
楽しみにしててくださね。
Look forward to it.
よし。
Alright.
それでは、聴いてください。「SUPERNOVA」。
Please listen to: 'SUPERNOVA'.
Woah-oh-oh-oh-oh...
甘く ほろ苦い夢
A sweet and bittersweet dream
「これでいい」が 「これがいい」が
Between 'This is fine' and 'This is what I want'
折れかけたあの日
On that day when I almost broke
ここに間違いはなくて
There was no mistake here
正解もなくて自分次第で
There's no right answer, it's up to you
怖くて仕方ないけど
I'm scared and can't help it
誰かじゃない君と見たい景色は鮮明で
But the scenery I want to see with you, not anyone else, is vivid
Yeah!
それじゃあ、ここで足踏みなんか
Well then, I can't just stand still here!
していられないじゃん！
I've gotta go!
Oh Yeah!! 無数の星の中
Oh Yeah!! Among countless stars
光は君がくれた
You gave me the light
もっと 超えて行けるさ
I can go even further
SUPERNOVA 起こせ 今！
Cause a SUPERNOVA, now!
Oh Yeah!! 何度だって翔べる
Oh Yeah!! I can fly as many times as it takes
これは紛れもなく僕らの軌跡
This is undeniably our trajectory
Hi Friends!
Woah-oh-oh-oh-oh...
心、泣きじゃくる日でも
Even on days when your heart is wailing
いつだってここに おいで
You can always come here
強がりはらしくないよ
Acting tough isn't like you
"ひとり"じゃない　君もほら　僕ら手取り合って
Not "alone". You see, let's take each other's hands.
笑おう！叫ぼう！あの宇宙の向こうへ
Let's laugh! Let's shout! Towards the other side of that universe.
Oh Yeah!! 無数の星の中
Oh Yeah!! Amidst the countless stars,
Oh Yeah!! 交わした約束も
Oh Yeah!! even the promises we made,
きっと　叶えられるさ
will surely come true.
Oh Yeah!! SUPERNOVA　翔ける今！
Oh Yeah!! SUPERNOVA, soaring now!
Oh Yeah!! 誰一人欠かせない
Oh Yeah!! Not a single person can be missed.
あの日描いた夢の先まで
To the end of the dream we drew that day.
Hi Friends!
こんな現在を愛せるように
So that I can love the present like this.
君に向けて歌おう　心が叫んでる！
Let's sing for you. My heart is shouting!
Oh Yeah!! 無数の星の中
Oh Yeah!! Amidst the countless stars,
Oh Yeah!! 光は君がくれた
Oh Yeah!! you gave me the light.
もっと　越えていけるさ
We can surely go even further.
Oh Yeah!! SUPERNOVA　起こせ今！
Oh Yeah!! SUPERNOVA, let's make it happen now!
Oh Yeah!! 何度だって飛べる
Oh Yeah!! We can fly as many times as it takes.
これは紛れもなく僕らの軌跡
This is undoubtedly our miracle.
普通も当たり前も無い　君が君らしく在れるように
Neither normal nor ordinary exists. So that you can be yourself.
もっとずっと　届けよう
Let's keep delivering more and more.
不思議と怖くはないんだ　綺麗事、絵空事でもない
Strangely, I'm not afraid. It's neither a platitude nor a fabrication.
さあ、行こう！　この物語は終わらない！
Come on, let's go! This story will never end!
白いキツネの子は手を掲げ歌い、その歌声が広場に響き渡ると、
The white fox child raised her hand and sang, and as her singing voice echoed throughout the plaza,
人々の心は希望に満ち溢れ、1人、また1人と歌声が響き渡り
people's hearts were filled with hope, and one by one, the singing voices resonated,
街は光に包まれました。そしてついに…
and the town was enveloped in light. And finally...
白いキツネの子の夢は現実となり　平和な王国ははるか未来まで続いていくのでした。
the white fox child's dream became a reality, and the peaceful kingdom continued far into the future.
めでたし、めでたし。
And they lived happily ever after.
すこん部へ
To Sukon-bu
君が居てくれるおかげで
Thanks to you being there,
これまで頑張ってこれたよ
I've been able to work hard until now.
そんな君と、これから先も
With you, from now on too,
フブキングダム　この場所を守っていきたい
FBKINGDOM, I want to protect this place.
心からのありがとう
A heartfelt thank you.
そして
And,
１００万回の愛してるを届けます
I send you a million 'I love you's.
2025.1.15
白上フブキ 1st Album 発売決定
Shirakami Fubuki 1st Album release confirmed.
FBKINGDOM "Blessing"
フブキングダムとみんなに祝福を込めて...
With blessings to FBKINGDOM and everyone...
国民の皆様、
Citizens,
大変お待たせいたしました。
thank you so much for waiting.
白上フブキ、ファーストアルバム
Shirakami Fubuki's first album,
「FBKINGDOM Blessing」の発売が
the release of "FBKINGDOM Blessing"
来年、1月15日に決定いたしました！
has been set for next year, January 15th!
「FBKINGDOM」をコンセプトに、
With "FBKINGDOM" as the concept,
ファーストシングル「Say!ファンファーレ!」など既存曲5曲に加え、
along with 5 existing songs like the first single "Say! Fanfare!",
新曲を、なんと9曲新たに収録しております。
it features a whopping 9 brand new songs.
Revoさん、藤永龍太郎さん、小池竜暉さん、久保直樹さんら
With Revo, Ryutaro Fujinaga, Ryuki Koike, Naoki Kubo,
豪華作曲陣の皆様に、アルバムに向けた新曲を書き下ろしていただきました。
and other amazing composers, they have written new songs for this album.
ポップ、ロック、
Pop, Rock,
バラード、ファンタジックなものまで、
Ballads, and even fantasy-themed songs,
様々な楽曲にチャレンジしてますので、
I'm challenging myself with various genres,
ぜひ、今からどんなアルバムになるか楽しみにしてて下さいね。
so please look forward to seeing what kind of album it becomes.
アルバムのイラストは、凪白みと先生に描いていただきました。
The album illustration was drawn by Mito Nagishiro-sensei.
この王様白上、うーん、かわちい！
This King Shirakami, mmm, so cute!
皆さんもぜひお手にとって、じっくり見て下さいね。
Everyone, please get a copy and take a good look at it.
そして今回、数量限定版もご用意！
And this time, we've also prepared a Limited Edition!
数量限定版は、特別ワンピースボックス仕様となっており、
The Limited Edition comes in a special one-piece box,
CDジャケットの表情は、にっこり笑顔の表情差分イラスト。
and the CD jacket features a variant illustration with a big smile.
このジャケットは、こちらの数量限定版オリジナルバージョンとなっております。
This jacket is exclusive to this Limited Edition version.
封入特典として、アクリルスタンド、
As internal bonuses, an acrylic stand,
ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームのPRカード、
a Hololive Official Card Game PR card,
さらに、このジャケットイラストで白上が手に持っている、
Also, the jacket illustration shows Shirakami holding
「FBKINGDOM」からの招待状が入っております。
an invitation from "FBKINGDOM," which is included.
何が書かれているかは、届いてからのお楽しみ！
What's written inside is a surprise for when it arrives!
数量限定版は、本日このあと21時30分から
The Limited Edition will be available starting today at 21:30
ホロライブオフィシャルショップにて先着順で購入いただけます。
at the Hololive Official Shop on a first-come, first-served basis.
さらにさらにすごい！
And it gets even better!
通常版は、全国のCDショップでの販売が決定じゃい！ありがとうございます！
The regular edition will be sold at CD shops nationwide! Thank you!
それぞれのCDショップにて、購入者特典が付いてきます。
Each CD shop will have its own purchase bonus.
たくさん種類があるので、迷ってしまうかもしれませんが、
There are so many types that you might have trouble choosing,
ぜひ、いろんなCDショップページをチェックしてみてくださいね。
but please check out the pages of various CD shops.
特典のデザインは、後日公開しますので、そちらもお楽しみに！
The designs for the bonuses will be revealed at a later date, so look forward to that too!
ファーストアルバム「FBKINGDOM Blessing」の情報は、
Information about the first album "FBKINGDOM Blessing"
このあと21時30分オープンの、
is summarized on the special website opening at 21:30,
アルバム特設サイトにてまとめて掲載しております。
accessible after this broadcast.
アルバムに関するハッシュタグは、
The hashtag for the album is
ハッシュタグ「DearFBKINGDOM」
Hashtag "DearFBKINGDOM"
このあと21時30分から予約開始となりますので、
Pre-orders will start from 21:30 today,
国民の皆さん、ぜひよろしくお願いいたします。
so citizens, I hope for your continued support.
（国民）のみんなへ！！
To all my citizens!!
新衣装やアルバムびっくりしたかなぁ？
Were you surprised by the new outfit and the album?
白上からの～サプライ～ズ！（えっへん）
A surprise~ from Shirakami! (Ehem)
毎日応援してくれてありがとうね
Thank you for supporting me every day
これからも夢を見させて！
Please keep letting me dream!
FBKINGDOMの教祖さまより
From the leader of FBKINGDOM
Shirakami Fubuki